Guide to the Pennsylvania Canals Publications Collection, 1835,1963-1979 AIS.1979.16
ULS Archives & Special Collections
Pennsylvania Canals Publications Collection
1835, 1963-1979
ULS Archives & Special Collections
Leuba, Walter
AIS.1979.16
0.5 Linear Feet (1 box)
The collection of Pennsylvania Canals Publications consists of a book, The Pennsylvania Main Line Canal and several pamphlets and periodicals detailing the different canals across the state of Pennsylvania.
Scope and Content Notes
This collection consists of pamphlets and a book, The Pennsylvania Main Line Canal, authored jointly by Mr. Walter Leuba and Dr. Robert McCullough. While the weekly installment format is available in this collection, the book and all correspondence relating to it are retained by the Special Collections Department of the University of Pittsburgh Libraries.
Access Restrictions
No restrictions.
Acquisition Information
This collection was a gift from Walter Leuba in 1979.
Previous Citation
Pennsylvania Canals Publications Collection, 1835, 1963-1979, AIS.1979.16, Archives Service Center, University of Pittsburgh
Pennsylvania Canals Collectanea, AIS 79:16, Archives of Industrial Society, University of Pittsburgh
Societies; Business and Industry; Transportation; Canals -- Pennsylvania; American Canal Society; Leuba, Walter
- The Pennsylvania Main Line Canal, April 18, 1963 - December 26, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Aungst, Dean M. The Two Canals of Lebanon County, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Brenner, Fred J. Hiking With History Along the Erie Extentsion Canal, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Hahn, Thomas F. Towpath Guide to the Chesapeake Ohio Canal, 1971,1972 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Klein, Theodore B. The Canals of Pennsylvania and the System of Internal Improvements, June 30, 1900 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Jacobs, Harry A. The Juniata Canal and Old Portage Railroad, 1941,1969 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Mitchell's Compendium of the Internal Improvements of the United States, 1835 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Nicklin, Philip. Journey Through Pennsylvania, 1835 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Shankl, William H. Indian Trails to Superhighways, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Shank, William H. The Amazing Pennsylvania Canals, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Shank, William H. Great Floods of Pennsylvania, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Stephenson, Clarence D. The Pennsylvania Canal, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Vogel, Robert M. Roebling's Delaware Hudson Canal Aquaducts, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Welch, Sylvester Allegheny Portage Railroad, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Miscellaneous (pamphlets,brochures, nine total items) (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Canal Currents: Bulletin of the Pennsylvania Canal Society, 1968-1979 (Box 1, Folder 16-19)
- American Canals: Bulletin of the American Canal Society, 1972-1975 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Pennsylvania Canal Society by-laws, announcements of meetings, tours, applications, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 21-22)
- American Canal Society (announcements of meetings, tours, applications) (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Publication Advertisements (Box 1, Folder 24)